

ABOUT

Howdy! I'm a front end engineer with over five years of experience building web applications that focus on accessibility and ease of maintenance. I am interested in creative code and am in the process of advancing my UX, UI, and design skills so that I may pursue full-stack design roles. I'm also an illustrator, an avid language learner, and a virgo.

TECHNOLOGIES

Code: Advanced Custom Fields, CSS, HTML, Frontity, GatsbyJS, Git, GSAP, Gulp, Javascript, JQuery, PHP, React.js, SASS, styled-components, three.js, WebGL, Webpack, Wordpress

Design: Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Figma, Procreate, Sketch, Spline

EXPERIENCE

known.creative

Senior Front End Engineer (Jan 2016 - June 2021)

Led projects from UX ideation to post-launch support, executing responsive and performant builds that met functional requirements within expected timelines.

Streamlined development workflow by 20% while improving output quality by engineering a boilerplate Wordpress theme on which all agency projects were initiated thereafter

Brought accessibility awareness to agency by establishing procedure ensuring minimum A level ADA compliance on all projects

Established technical support flow between engineers and clients, streamlining the ticketing process and improving code extensibility through direct communications regarding project requirements

Increased cross-departmental understanding at handoff by collaborating in the UX phase and enforcing accessibility standards in design reviews

Trained clients in Wordpress site administration and upkeep through group sessions and robust documentation, decreasing support requests by nearly half

Produced illustrative assets for client packaging, promotional materials, and ebooks.

Santoro Design

Designer-Developer, Consultant (Oct 2020 - present)

Authored, distributed, and presented user research to improve team understanding of specialized project needs for niche user communities

Reviewed 100% of project assets and UX flows to ensure full ADA compliance and advised on strategies that streamlined user experience.

Developed and deployed Wordpress applications with cross-platform event integration and custom resource taxonomy.

Freelance

Designer-Developer, Consultant (Nov 2015 - present)

Worked with clients to design, wireframe, and build web experiences from scratch or move existing projects in new directions. Responsibilities vary by project from including brand strategy to asset creation and beyond.

CLIENTS OF NOTE





















EDUCATION

Smith College (3.85/4.0)

B.A. Government, Chinese - (2009-2013)

Honors: First Group Scholar (graduation within top 10% of class), Ettie Chin Hong Prize (excellence in the study of East Asian Language), Dean's List